<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Choria Application Builder Documentation</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/index.html</link><description>Recent content on Choria Application Builder Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quick Start</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/quick-start/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/quick-start/index.html</guid><description>Installation Over on our Releases page you will find binaries, rpms, debs, zip files and more holding the appbuilder command. There is just one command and you can place it anywhere in your path.
If your editor supports it there is a JSON Schema for the definition.
We publish OS X and Linux homebrew packages:
brew tap choria-io/tap brew install choria-io/tap/appbuilderHello World We will make a little command that invokes cowsay to demonstrate some of the capabilities of the system.</description></item><item><title>Reference</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/index.html</guid><description>Command Components The system primarily is there to execute a type of command somewhere in the hierarchy of a CLI tools sub commands.
Lets say we have an app called demo that has commands demo say and demo think the say and think bits are commands. In this example these are commands of type exec - they run a shell command.
If we had a command demo deploy status and demo deploy upgrade then generally the deploy would not perform any action, it&amp;rsquo;s there mainly to achor sub commands and show help information.</description></item><item><title>Local Task Mode</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/tasks/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/tasks/index.html</guid><description>Some features are ongoing experiments and not part of the supported feature set, this section will call them out.
Local Task Mode While it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have a formal machine-wide command that behaves like a normal Unix CLI command I found I would like to use this same framework to build project specific helpers.
Version Hint This is available since version 0.6.2 and GA since 0.9.0.
Imagine you have a development project and have utility commands to update dependencies, serve the documentation in preview mode, run tests or build custom binaries.</description></item><item><title>Experiments</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/experiments/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/experiments/index.html</guid><description>Some features are ongoing experiments and not part of the supported feature set, this section will call them out.
Form based data generation wizards The general flow of applications is to expose Arguments and Flags when then can be used in templates to create files or render some output. This works quite well but can be limiting for more complex needs.
So we are introducing a full wizard style question-and-answer system that let you guide users through help, questions, validations and more to construct complex data.</description></item></channel></rss>