<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reference on Choria Application Builder Documentation</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Reference on Choria Application Builder Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Common Settings</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/common-settings/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/common-settings/index.html</guid><description>Command Types As we saw above we have parent and exec types of commands. Users can add more but these are the core ones we support today.
Most commands are made up of a generic set of options and then have one or more added in addition to specialise them.
Common properties reference Most commands include a standard set of fields - those that do not or have special restritions will mention in the docs.</description></item><item><title>Parent Command</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/parent/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/parent/index.html</guid><description>A parent is a placeholder, you can have a command like example deploy status and example deploy upgrade, here the deploy is a parent. It&amp;rsquo;s just there to group related commands and takes no action on it&amp;rsquo;s own.
It requires the the name, description, type and commands and the optional aliases.
It does not accept flags, arguments or confirm_prompt.
name: deploy description: Manage deployment of the system type: parent # Commands are required for the parent type and should have more than 1 commands: []Including commands from a file The include_file option allows loading the parent command definition from an external YAML file.</description></item><item><title>Exec Command</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/exec/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/exec/index.html</guid><description>Use the exec command to execute commands found in your shell, and, optionally format their output through JQ.
The exec command supports data transformations.
Running commands An exec runs a command, it is identical to the generic example shown earlier and accepts flags, arguments and sub commands. The only difference is that it adds a command, environment (since 0.0.3) and transform (since 0.0.5) items.
Below the example that runs cowsay integrated with configuration:</description></item><item><title>Form Command</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/form/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/form/index.html</guid><description>Use the form command to create guided wizard style question-and-answer sessions that construct complex data from user input.
The general use case is to guide users through creating complex configuration files. The gathered data is output as JSON and can be sent to transforms for scaffolding or templating into a final form.
The form command supports data transformations, flags, arguments and sub commands.
Version Hint This was added in version 0.</description></item><item><title>Scaffold Command</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/scaffold/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/scaffold/index.html</guid><description>Use the scaffold command to create directories of files based on templates.
The Sprig functions library is available to use in templates.
Version Hint This was added in version 0.7.0
Scaffolding files First we will just show the most basic example:
name: scaffold description: Demonstrate scaffold features by creating some go files type: scaffold arguments: - name: target description: The target to create the files in required: true target: &amp;#34;{{ .</description></item><item><title>Choria Discover Command</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/discovery/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/discovery/index.html</guid><description>The Discover command interact with the Choria Discovery system used to find fleet nodes based on a vast array of possible queries and data sources.
Since this is built into Choria it will simply use your Choria Client configuration for the user executing the command to find the Choria Brokers and more. It supports the usual override methods such as creating a choria.conf file in your project working directory. No connection properties are required or supported.</description></item><item><title>Choria RPC Command</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/rpc/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/rpc/index.html</guid><description>The RPC command interact with the Choria RPC system used execute actions on remote nodes.
Since this is built into Choria it will simply use your Choria Client configuration for the user executing the command to find the Choria Brokers and more. It supports the usual override methods such as creating a choria.conf file in your project working directory. No connection properties are required or supported.
Before using this command type I suggest reading about Choria Concepts.</description></item><item><title>Choria KV Command</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/kv/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/kv/index.html</guid><description>The KV command interact with the Choria Key-Value Store and supports usual operations such as Get, Put, Delete and more.
Since this is built into Choria it will simply use your Choria Client configuration for the user executing the command to find the Choria Brokers and more. It supports the usual override methods such as creating a choria.conf file in your project working directory. No connection properties are required or supported.</description></item><item><title>Templating</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/templating/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/templating/index.html</guid><description>Templates allow you to interpolate values from Flags, Arguments and Configuration into some aspects of commands.
For example the exec command type allows you to use templates to put arguments into the command being run.
We use the Go template language at the moment, it&amp;rsquo;s not the best we might look at something else later.
Only some fields are parsed through templates, the documentation for each command type will call out what is supported.</description></item><item><title>Transformations</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/transformations/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/transformations/index.html</guid><description>Transformations is like a shell pipe defined in App Builder. We have a number of transformations and using them is entirely optional - often a shell pipe would be much better.
The reason for adding transformations like jq to App Builder itself is to have it function in places where that 3rd party dependency is not met. Rather than require everyone to install JQ - and handle that dependency, we just add a JQ dialect directly to App Builder.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/configuration/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/configuration/index.html</guid><description>To support supplying items like passwords, tokens, custom applications or paths we support loading a per-application configuration file.
This file is stored in example-cfg.yaml in the standard file locations.
It&amp;rsquo;s any valid YAML file, for example:
# /etc/appbuilder/demo-cfg.yaml Cowsay: animalsayThis can then we used in templates. If a configuration item is required I suggest always using it with the require function:
command: | slack-notify --token &amp;#34;{{.Config.slack.token | require &amp;#34;slack token not set&amp;#34; }}&amp;#34;</description></item><item><title>Cheat Sheets</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/cheats/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/cheats/index.html</guid><description>While output from --help can be useful, many people just don&amp;rsquo;t read it or understand the particular format and syntax shown. Instead, a quick cheat sheet style help can often be more helpful.
There is a great utility called cheat that solves this problem in a generic manner, by allowing searching, indexing and rendering of cheat sheets in your terminal.
$ cheat tar # To extract an uncompressed archive: tar -xvf /path/to/foo.</description></item><item><title>File Locations</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/file-locations/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/file-locations/index.html</guid><description>The only configuration you should be concerned about is your Application Definition and optional Application Configuration.
We support the XDG Base specification, including standard environment variable based overrides like using XDG_CONFIG_HOME, for storing these in your home directory and have system wide fallback locations.
Files are stored in either /etc/appbuilder/ or ~/.config/appbuilder (~/Library/Application Support/appbuilder on a Mac). When the symlink is created to a choria binary the locations /etc/choria/builder and ~/.</description></item><item><title>Runtime Settings and Tools</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/running-validation/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/running-validation/index.html</guid><description>When just invoking appbuilder various utilities are exposed, your apps also take some Environment Variables as runtime configuration.
Builder Info General runtime information can be printed:
$ appbuilder info Choria Application Builder Debug Logging (BUILDER_DEBUG): false Configuration File (BUILDER_CONFIG): not specified Definition File (BUILDER_APP): not specified Source Locations: /home/example/.config/appbuilder, /etc/appbuilderHere we can see where applications are loaded from and more.
Run Time Configuration As seen above a few variables are consulted, below a list with details:</description></item><item><title>Compiled Applications</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/compile/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/appbuilder/reference/compile/index.html</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s nice that you do not need to compile App Builder apps into binaries as it allows for fast iteration, but sometimes it might be desired.
Version Hint This was added in version 0.7.2
Basic compiled application Given an application in app.yaml we can create a small Go stub:
package main import ( &amp;#34;context&amp;#34; _ &amp;#34;embed&amp;#34; &amp;#34;os&amp;#34; &amp;#34;github.com/choria-io/appbuilder/builder&amp;#34; &amp;#34;github.com/choria-io/fisk&amp;#34; ) //go:embed app.</description></item></channel></rss>